{"data":[{"question":"That pipe _____ (leak) for ages. We must get it mended.","a":"has been leaking","b":"have been leaking","answer":"1","explain":"- Present Perfect Continuous:\n+ Show that something started in the past and has continued up until now.\n+ Singular: Has+ PP.\n+ Plural: Have +PP.","category":"2","subcategorylv1":"6","subcategorylv2":"1","type":"7"},{"question":"How long you _____ (wear) glasses?","a":"has you been wearing","b":"have you been wearing","answer":"2","explain":"- We use the present perfect continuous to say how long for an activity that happened in the past, continues and still happening now","category":"2","subcategorylv1":"6","subcategorylv2":"1","type":"7"},{"question":"We _____ (live) here since 1977.","a":"has been living","b":"have been living","answer":"2","explain":"-  We use the present perfect continuous to say how long for an activity that happened in the past, continues and still happening now(since 1977)","category":"2","subcategorylv1":"6","subcategorylv2":"1","type":"7"},{"question":"You _____ (drive) all day. Let me drive now.","a":"has been driving","b":"have been driving","answer":"2","explain":"- We use the present perfect continuous to emphasize how long for an activity that's still happening now (all day)\n- Have\/has + been + V-ing","category":"2","subcategorylv1":"6","subcategorylv2":"1","type":"7"},{"question":"You _____ (not eat) enough lately. That's why you feel irritable.","a":"hasn't been eating","b":"haven't been eating","answer":"2","explain":"- The negative form: Have\/ has + not + been + V-ing","category":"2","subcategorylv1":"6","subcategorylv2":"1","type":"7"},{"question":"It _____ (rain) for two days now. There'll be a flood soon.","a":"has been raining","b":"have been raining","answer":"1","explain":"- We use the present perfect continuous to say how long for an activity that happened in the past, continues and still happening now (for two days now)\n- It + has + been + V-ing...","category":"2","subcategorylv1":"6","subcategorylv2":"1","type":"7"},{"question":"I _____ (shop) all day and I haven't a penny left.","a":"has been shopping","b":"have been shopping","answer":"2","explain":"- We use the present perfect continuous to say how long for an activity that happened in the past, continues and still happening now(all day)\n- I have been + V-ing...","category":"2","subcategorylv1":"6","subcategorylv2":"1","type":"7"},{"question":"It _____ (snow) for three days now. The roads will be blocked if it doesn't stop soon.","a":"has been snowing","b":"have been snowing","answer":"1","explain":"- We use the present perfect continuous to say how long for an activity that happened in the past, continues and still happening now (for three days now) \n- It has + been + V-ing...","category":"2","subcategorylv1":"6","subcategorylv2":"1","type":"7"},{"question":"The petrol gauge _____ (say) \"Empty\" for quite a long time now. Don't think we should get some petrol?","a":"has been saying","b":"have been saying","answer":"1","explain":"- We use the present perfect continuous to say how long for an activity that happened in the past, continues and still happening now (for quite a long time now)","category":"2","subcategorylv1":"6","subcategorylv2":"1","type":"7"},{"question":"Have you seen my bag anywhere? I _____ (look) for it for ages.","a":"has been looking","b":"have been looking","answer":"2","explain":"- We use the present perfect continuous to say how long for an activity that happened in the past, continues and still happening now(for ages)\n- I have been looking...","category":"2","subcategorylv1":"6","subcategorylv2":"1","type":"7"}]}